Guide to the DeLange Conference Collection, 1988-2016 UA 263
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
DeLange Conference Collection
1988-2016
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Wilson, Rick, Dr.
UA 263
4.5 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
This collection is composed of papers and media relating to the DeLange Conferences held at Rice University. It includes correspondence, marketing materials, conference materials, reports, photographs, and electronic media that document the preparation leading up to the conferences and the activities during conferences.
Biographical / Historical
The DeLange Conferences are made possible by an endowment established at Rice University by C. M. and Demaris Hudspeth in memory of Demaris' parents, Albert J. and Demaris Crowley DeLange. These conferences began in 1991 and are held every two to four years. They have the flexibility to range broadly in subject matter and discipline. All are intended to bring to the Rice University campus top experts and major figures to focus on a topic of great concern to society. Focusing on diverse topics such as the environment, human behavior, medicine, libraries, art museums, universities, information technology, and city planning, the conferences have occurred periodically since 1991, usually on the Rice campus and often co-sponsored by other organizations. Speakers are recruited internationally. Four conferences resulted in published books.
Excerpted from the DeLange Conference website: http://delange.rice.edu.
Scope and Contents
The collection is composed of documents, photographic material, and electronic media that document the activities before, during, and after the DeLange conferences. The materials are in good condition and include correspondence, conference materials, marketing materials, reports, photographic material, and audio, visual, and electronic media.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The material was transferred to the Woodson Research Center in May 2017 by Dr. Rick Wilson of Scientia/DeLange.
Related Materials
There is some administrative overlap with the Scientia Organizational papers (UA 206). See also scientia.rice.edu.
Index Terms
Subjects
Education; Medicine; Sustainable development; bioengineering; Libraries; Health care and medicine
Document Types
videotapes; audiotapes; letters (correspondence); photographs
Subjects (Persons)
Wilson, Rick, Dr.
- Series I: Conferences I-VI
  - History and general Information (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - I, Human impact on the Environment, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - II, Biotechnology, Planning, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - II, Biotechnology, Program and publicity, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - III, Sustainable Development, Planning and publicity, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - III, Sustainable Development, Program, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - IV, Neurobiology, Planning minutes, correspondence, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - IV, Neurobiology, Attendees, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - IV, Neurobiology, Program, publicity, stationery, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - IV, Neurobiology, Speakers, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - IV, Neurobiology, Book, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - V, Frontiers of Medicine, Planning, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - V, Frontiers of Medicine, Planning, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - V, Frontiers of Medicine, Planning, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - V, Frontiers of Medicine, Programs, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - V, Frontiers of Medicine, Publicity, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - V, Frontiers of Medicine, Speakers, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - V, Frontiers of Medicine, Attendees, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - V, Frontiers of Medicine, Reports, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - VI, The Emerging Library, Planning, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - VI, The Emerging Library, Planning, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - VI, The Emerging Library, Program, publicity, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - VI, The Emerging Library, Speakers, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - VI, The Emerging Library, Attendees, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Series II: Photographs
  - Conference V, color prints, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Conference V, color prints, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Conference V, negatives, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Conference VIII, one index sheet, one color photo, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Series III: Audio, Visual, and Electronic Media
  - Second DeLange Conference, Opening Remarks - day 1, Larry V. McIntire, Malcolm Gillis, Kathleen S. Matthews, C. Thomas Caskey (cont.), (2 tapes), 1994 (Box 3, Tape 1-2)
  - Second DeLange Conference, C. Thomas Caskey (cont.) and Anna Marie Skalka (cont.) #2 (3 tapes), 1994 (Box 3, Tape 3-5)
  - Second DeLange Conference #3, 1994 (Box 3, Tape 6)
  - Second DeLange Conference, #4, 1994 (Box 3, Tape 7)
  - Second DeLange Conference #5, Daniel E. Koshland Jr. (cont.) and Barbara Mishkin (part), (3tapes), 1994 (Box 3, Tape 8-10)
  - Second DeLange Conference #6, Opening Remarks - day 2, Larry V. McIntire, Michael Shuler, Eric Tomlinson (cont.), (4 tapes), 1994 (Box 3, Tape 11-14)
  - Second DeLange Conference #7, Eric Tomlinson (cont.) and Louis Lasagna (cont.), 1994 (Box 3, Tape 21)
  - Second DeLange Conference #8, Louis Lasagna, Jerome Schultz, Rebecca Eisenberg (cont.), (2 tapes), 1994 (Box 3, Tape 22-23)
  - Second DeLange Conference #9, Jose E. Trias, (3 tapes), 1994 (Box 3, Tape 24-26)
  - Second DeLange Conference #10, Rebecca Eisenberg (cont.) and Neal F. Lane, (3 tapes, 1994 (Box 3, Tape 27-29)
  - Second DeLange Conference #11, Opening Remarks - day 3, Kathleen S. Matthews, M.R.C. Greenwood, Robert M. Nerem, Savio L.C. Woo, (3 tapes), 1994 (Box 3, Tape 30-32)
  - Second DeLange Conference #12, Savio Woo (cont.), (2tapes), 1994 (Box 3, Tape 33-34)
  - Second DeLange Conference #13, (3 tapes), 1994 (Box 3, Tape 31-33)
  - Second DeLange Conference #14, Mark Rothstein and Ruth Ellen Bulger, (3 tapes), 1994 (Box 3, Tape 34-36)
  - Second DeLange Conference #15, Gene F. Parkin, (2 tapes), 1994 (Box 3, Tape 37-38)
  - Second DeLange Conference #16, Suzanne Holmes Giannini, Closing Remarks, (3 tapes), 1994 (Box 3, Tape 36-38)
  - DeLange Conference Banquet Speech (4 tapes), 1994 (Box 3, Tape 39-42)
  - Highlights from Delange Conference, 1991 (Box 4, Tape 1)
  - DeLange Conf. Tape #4 Keynote, 2005 (Box 4, Tape 2)
  - Lee Hood fixed for streaming, n.d. (Box 4, Tape 3)
  - Lee Hood PowerPoint, n.d. (Box 4, Tape 4)
  - Rice DeLange Conf. (switcher), Tape 1, 2005-03-07 (Box 4, Tape 5)
  - Rice DeLange Conf. (camera), Tape 1, 2005-03-07 (Box 4, Tape 6)
  - Rice DeLange Conf. (switcher), Tape 2, 2005-03-07 (Box 4, Tape 7)
  - Rice DeLange Conf. (camera), Tape 2, 2005-03-07 (Box 4, Tape 8)
  - Rice DeLange Conf. (switcher), Tape 3, 2005-03-07 (Box 4, Tape 9)
  - Rice DeLange Conf. (camera), Tape 4, 2005-03-08 (Box 4, Tape 10)
  - Rice DeLange Conf. (switcher), Tape 5, 2005-03-08 (Box 4, Tape 11)
  - Rice DeLange Conf. (camera), Tape 5, 2005-03-08 (Box 4, Tape 12)
  - Rice DeLange Conf. (switcher), Tape 6, 2005-03-08 (Box 4, Tape 13)
  - Rice DeLange Conf. (camera), Tape 6, 2005-03-08 (Box 4, Tape 14)
  - Rice DeLange Conf., Tape 7, 2005-03-08 (Box 4, Tape 15)
  - Rice DeLange Conf., Tape 8, 2005-03-08 (Box 4, Tape 16)
  - Rice DeLange Conf. (switcher), Tape 9, 2005-03-09 (Box 4, Tape 17)
  - Rice DeLange Conf. (camera), Tape 9, 2005-03-09 (Box 4, Tape 18)
  - Rice DeLange Conf. (switcher), Tape 10, 2005-03-09 (Box 4, Tape 19)
  - Rice DeLange Conf. (camera), Tape 10, 2005-03-09 (Box 4, Tape 20)
  - DeLange A.M. #1, 1994-02-28 (Box 4, Cassette 21)
  - DeLange P.M. #2, 1994-02-28 (Box 4, Cassette 22)
  - DeLange A.M. #1, 1994-03-01 (Box 4, Cassette 23)
  - DeLange P.M. #1, 1994-03-01 (Box 4, Cassette 24)
  - DeLange A.M. #2, 1994-03-02 (Box 4, Cassette 25)
  - DeLange P.M. #2, 1994-03-02 (Box 4, Cassette 26)
  - DeLange A.M. #2, 1994-03-02 (Box 4, Cassette 27)
  - DeLange P.M. #2 (2 tapes), 1994-03-02 (Box 4, Cassette 28-29)
  - DeLange P.M. #1, 1994-03-02 (Box 4, Cassette 30)
  - DeLange Conf., Posner, Michael and Fan, Jin Biography/Abstract (Box 4, Disc 31)
  - DeLange, Doupe Abstract, n.d. (Box 4, Disc 32)
  - DeLange IV, Eichenbaum, n.d. (Box 4, Disc 33)
  - Ellen (Personal) Part 1 (Scientia/Delange), n.d. (Box 4, Disc 34)
  - Ellen (Personal) Part III, n.d. (Box 4, Disc 35)
  - DeLange III Conference Mac Format, n.d. (Box 4, Disc 36)
  - DeLange IV PC Format, 2001 (Box 4, Disc 37)
  - DeLange IV Mac ( 2 discs), 2001 (Box 4, Disc 38-39)
  - 5th DeLange Conf. (History), 2005 (Box 4, Disc 40)
  - 6th DeLange Conf. (History), n.d. (Box 4, Disc 41)
  - DeLange V 1, n.d. (Box 4, Disc 42)
  - DeLange V 2, n.d. (Box 4, Disc 43)
  - DeLange V 3, n.d. (Box 4, Disc 44)
  - DeLange V 4, n.d. (Box 4, Disc 45)
  - DeLange V 5, n.d. (Box 4, Disc 46)
  - DeLange V 6, n.d. (Box 4, Disc 47)
  - DeLange V 8, n.d. (Box 4, Disc 48)
  - DeLange V, tif files, copied 5/05, n.d. (Box 4, Disc 49)
  - DeLange Presos, Pangalos, Nicolson, Greenfield 9, n.d. (Box 4, Disc 50)
  - DeLange Conf. Wallpaper, n.d. (Box 4, Disc 51)
  - DeLange Conference V (2 discs), 2005-03 (Box 4, Disc 52-53)
  - DeLange 1st Day PowerPoints (Tony), 2005 (Box 4, Disc 54)
  - D.M. Engelman, Folding and Evolution of Membrane Proteins, #10 (Box 4, Disc 55)
  - DeLange Conf., Schultz 8:15 A.M., 11, n.d. (Box 4, Disc 56)
  - DeLange Conference VI Program Files (Ellen Butler), 2007-03 (Box 4, Disc 57)
  - Delange Tape 2, Matthews, Skalka, Intro, Wlodawer, Questions, n.d. (Box 4, Cassette 58)
  - Delange Tape 5, Intro & Remarks- McIntire, Shuler, Tomlinson, Questions, Intro for Lasagna, n.d. (Box 4, Cassette 59)
  - Delange Tape 6, Lasagna, Questions, Schultz, Trias, n.d. (Box 4, Cassette 60)
  - Delange Tape 7, Eisenberg, Lane, Discussion, n.d. (Box 4, Cassette 61)
  - DeLange Tape 9, 1994 (Box 4, Cassette 62)
  - DeLange meeting, core group (Prego restaurant), n.d. (Box 4, Cassette 63)
  - Core Group Meeting #2 Prego, 2004-05-03 (Box 4, Cassette 64)
  - DeLange Scientia Mtg., 2003-12-02 (Box 4, Cassette 65)
- Series IV: Conferences VII-X
  - Conference VII, Transforming the Metropolis, Planning, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Conference VII, Transforming the Metropolis, Planning, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Conference VII, Transforming the Metropolis, Program and reports, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Conference VIII, Research University, Planning, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Conference VIII, Research University, Planning, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Conference VIII, Research University, Program and Publicity, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Conference VIII, Research University, Attendees, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Conference VIII, Research University, Topical articles, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Conference VIII, Research University, Topical articles, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Conference IX, Teaching in the University of Tomorrow, (proposal and advertisement), 2014 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Conference X, Humans, Machines, and the Future of Work, (advertisement), 2016 (Box 5, Folder 11)